<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Clément Weinreich's Website</title><link>https://clement-w.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Clément Weinreich's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://clement-w.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On the Curvature of Deep Generative Models</title><link>https://clement-w.github.io/posts/latentspaceoddity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://clement-w.github.io/posts/latentspaceoddity/</guid><description>According to the manifold hypothesis, high-dimensional data, despite its apparent complexity, often adheres to a simpler underlying structure, typically represented as a manifold, or a lower-dimensional surface embedded within the larger dimensional space. Performing computations within these high-dimensional environments presents significant challenges. A practical approach is to parameterize the surface in $\mathcal{X}$ by a low-dimensional variable $\mathbf{z} \in \mathcal{Z}$ created with a suitable smooth generator function $f : \mathcal{Z} \to \mathcal{X}$.</description></item><item><title>Semi-Discrete Optimal Transport for Texture Synthesis</title><link>https://clement-w.github.io/posts/textureot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://clement-w.github.io/posts/textureot/</guid><description>Texture synthesis is a technique that consists in generating some realistic textures by imitating the patterns of a given exemplar texture. It plays a crucial role in many domains such as computer graphics, where the synthesis quality directly impacts the visual quality and the realism of graphical environments. The objective is to have a realistic replica in a visual sense but with original content: we don’t simply want to copy parts of the original texture for the sake of visual quality and realism.</description></item><item><title>Mathematics of Diffusion models</title><link>https://clement-w.github.io/posts/diffusion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://clement-w.github.io/posts/diffusion/</guid><description>Introduction This blog post aims to develop and explain the mathematical foundations of diffusion models 1, and image-to-image diffusion models 2 3. This work is part of a larger project on image colorization using diffusion, which was done in collaboration with Brennan Whitfield, and Vivek Shome in 2022. This blog post is inspired by Lilian Weng&amp;rsquo;s blog post on diffusion models 4, but contains more details in the mathematical derivations, which may help in understanding certain aspects.</description></item></channel></rss>